## **ADRIENNE LEE**

## FRONT END DEVELOPER

## adriennelee.dev

adrienneklee@gmail.com







## PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a Front End Developer with 10 years experience in non-profit project management and sustainability. I have a passion for finding creative solutions to untangle complicated problems. My passion for tech is bolstered by my experience in corporate social responsibility and has fuelled me in developing accessible, meaningful and responsive web applications.

## **WEB DEV SKILLS**

- HTML5
- CSS3/SCSS
- Javascript
- jQuery
- React
- Git/ GitHub
- Firebase
- WordPress
- Paired/ Group Programming
- Accessibility
  Standards

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Juno College of Technology

Web Development Immersive Bootcamp Oct 2021 - Dec 2021 Intermediate Javascript Intro to Web Development

#### Ryerson University

Masters in Applied Science, Environmental Management and Policy Sept 2009 - May 2011

### **McMaster University**

Bachelors of Science, Biochemistry & Biomedical Science Sept 2004 - May 2007

### **FEATURED PROJECTS**

#### **Guess Who Ghibli**

## HTML5 | SASS | Javascript | REST APIs Paired Programming

A web application made with Vanilla JS. Users are provided clues to guess randomly generated characters from the magical world of Studio Ghibli.

## Live Link | GitHub Repo

### Safe Spaces Toronto

## HTML5 and CSS3 | React | REST APIs | Firebase

An application built with React that seeks to provide safe restroom access for gender nonconforming individuals. Safe Spaces utilizes data from the Refuge Washroom API, Navigator Geolocation, and Firebase.

## <u>Live Link</u> | <u>GitHub Repo</u>

### Sun Run

# HTML5 | CSS3 | React | REST APIs | Firebase Team Programming

A group project built with React, Sun Run utilizes multiple APIs and Firebase persistence. Sun Run allows users to plan runs based on dates, sunrise/sunset times, distance, and pace.

#### Live Link | GitHub Repo

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **DIRECTOR OF GLOBAL IMPACT**

Tourism Cares (Sept 2018 - Oct 2021)

- Developed and designed sustainable tourism digital training platform utilized by 2000+ professionals.
- Collaborated with 160+ travel and tech brands on corporate social responsibility strategies.
- Speaker: NY Times Travel Show 2020, TravelCon Boston.
- Featured in: The Washington Post

#### **DIRECTOR OF DEVELOPMENT**

promoted from Programs Manager after serving for 4 years G Adventures | Planeterra (July 2012 - Sept 2018)

- Worked cross-functionally with Software team to develop mobile fundraising app for consumer audience.
- Lead Foundation's website rebrand with UX team, hosted on Wordpress. Maintained website content.
- Oversaw annual \$1.5M budget and planning process, increased donor revenue by 19% in one calendar year.
- Directly managed and mentored a team of 4.